Guide to the William Everard Gardiner Transportation Collection M0326
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Photographs, Berkeley & Oakland
  - Oakland
    - Washington St. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Berkeley, University of California (17 enlargements) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Oakland (23 enlargements), 1869-1873 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Oakland (9 views near City Hall) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oakland/East Bay (38 prints, most unidentified) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Oakland/East Bay, misc.
    - Otis Johnson's parents (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Maps of Oakland business district, Ranchos, San Antonio Creek (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Piedmont. New High School, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - San Pablo Dam, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Photographs, San Francisco (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Cable cars; Cliff House (first-third) Clay Street Railroad lithograph of eqpt.
- Photographs, Transportation
  - Bridges
    - Bay Bridge construction, 1933-1936 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Oakland Estuary Bridges: Harrison St. Bridge, Webster St. Bridge wreck (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Carquinez Bridge construction; Golden Gate Bridge construction 1935; Oregon Coast Highway Bridge over Rogue River, at Gold Beach (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ferries
    - Ferries, Oakland Mole Terminal, Yerba Buena Island (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Zone, Harbor Tug & Barge Company (Box 9, Folder 4)
      This boat operated as a ferry when the Webster St. Bridge was out of commission.
  - Key System
    - Employees, 1915-1935 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Key Route Trolley Tripper, Greek Theater July 14, 1911; Key System employees at Greek Theater October 8, 1915; Employee's Picnic, Neptune Beach, September 24, 1921; Posing for Life-Saving Poster, November 1922; Toi. Key Route cook July 31, 1922; Key System baseball team August 9, 1925; On Key Ferry "Yerba Buena" October 13, 1935; unidentified print & negative; unidentified group portrait on boat
    - Other, 1925, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Bus No. B-19, 1925; Public Service truck, 1925; Key System Building, May 1934
  - Railroads
    - Central Pacific Railroad (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Locomotives, building and early operation of CPRR, including winter track conditions, stations, railyards, empolyees. Copies of prints belonging to Stanley Keefe November 1930
    - Other Locomotives (Box 9, Folder 8)
      California Central Railroad, Lousiville & Nashville Railroad No 235 & No.1766; Sacramento Valley Railroad "Pioneer"; San Francisco & Oakland Railroad "Liberty"; Santa Cruz & Felton Railroad No. 1 "Santa Cruz" and No.2 "Felton"; Southern Pacific "CP Huntington"; Southern Pacific of New Mexico No. 19; unidentified, etc. "prints and copy negatives from glass plate negatives."
    - Locomotives from D.L. Joslyn, gift of W.E. Gardiner (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Atlantic & Gulf Railroad; B&O Railroad; Camden & Ambey Railroad; Great Northern Railroad; reproductions of lithographs
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Billy Jones and Jack Shriner of Mill Valley Railroad wih family, 1890. Copied from an old print by Dr. Pimble; Stations/Depts: Haughton/Marysville 1960s; Oakland, SPRR 1967; Sacramento SPRR 1862; Sacramento SVRR & CP depots 1871; unidentified railyards: Time schedules & advertisements: Cal Pacific RR and steamer New World, Vallejo Route; Central and WEstern Pacific Railroad via Oakland ferry December 1869; CPRR extension of service to Cisco; Central Southern and Cal. Pac. RR schedule May 1874; SF&SJ RRR ad, timetable August 1866; SPRR ad emigrant sleeping cars
  - Ships (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Separated Materials
    Associated Oil Tanker; "Gov. Ames" 1890 lith; SS Diablo; SS Everett; SS Mei Ren; SS Pres. Cleveland (old Golden State); unidentified, etc.
  - Stagecoach, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    print and enlargement of the Ben Halladay, 1868, taken during a parade
  - Street Railways
    - Equipment (Box 9, Folder 14)
      GE car equipment (motors, generators, controllers, rheostats, contactors, etc.) with description in accompanying letter from HA Esmann, Sales Agent of the General Electric Co. to Gardiner in March 1927.
    - Oakland, Construction (Box 9, Folder 15)
      road work including rail installation, paving of Telegraph Avenue, etc.
    - Oakland, Employees (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Employees and officers of various Oakland street railways, many identified
    - Oakland, Streetcars (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Oakland Railroad Co. "Bobtail Car"; tracks of first line, 1869; Car No. 0, old horse car; Car nos. 15, 51, 61; Oakland, San Leandro & Haywards Electric Railway sprinkler car 1895, Car No. 100, Flat car No. 103
    - Oakland, Misc. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Alameda timetable c1899; Central Car station during strike of July 17-19, 1934; Elmhurst power station; Elmhurst shops 1895; Oakland RR Co. stock subscription; Oakland Station 1869; Oakland Traction Co. cable house, offices c.1904; Telegraph Ave. line schedules October 1911
    - streetcar, Salt Lake City, Utah (Box 9, Folder 19)